graphistudio.com 2019-08-23

# privacy | Graphistudio

PRIVACY AND COOKIE POLICY OF THIS WEBSITE 

**WHY THIS NOTICE**

The information is provided only for the site www.graphistudio.com (hereinafter referred to simply as “site”) and not for other websites that the user may consult through links on the site. The information is also based on Recommendation no. 2/2001 of 17 May 2001, Opinion no. 04/2012 on Cookie Consent Exemption of 7 June 2012 and Working Document 02/2013 providing guidance on obtaining consent for cookies of 2 October 2013 that the European authorities for the protection of personal data, gathered in the Group set up pursuant to Article. Directive 95/46/EC, have adopted to identify some minimum requirements for the collection of personal data online, and, in particular, the methods, times and nature of the information that data controllers must provide to users when they connect to web pages, regardless of the purpose of the connection.

**DATA CONTROLLER**

Following visiting this site, data relating to identified or identifiable natural persons (so-called interested parties) may be processed.

The controller of their processing is Graphistudio spa with registered office in Via M.te Raut, 1 | 33090 ARBA (PN) Italy, P.IVA 00298370933 – R.E.A. PN No 32987, in the person of its legal representative.

**METHOD AND PURPOSE OF PROCESSING**

The processing of data will be carried out in accordance with the rules in force and the principles of fairness, lawfulness, transparency, relevance, completeness and non excess of information, and the above data will be collected and recorded only for the purposes indicated below and kept for a period strictly necessary for the purposes themselves.

The processing may consist in the collection, recording, organization, storage, adaptation or modification, extraction, consultation, use, communication by transmission, dissemination or any other form available, limitation, cancellation or destruction of data and will be carried out with the help of electronic means suitable to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of the data.

The subjects or categories of subjects who, within the scope of the purposes illustrated below, may become aware of the data or to whom they may be communicated are, as involved in the organization of the site, the internal staff (administrative) and also external subjects (third party technical service providers, hosting providers, computer companies, couriers) also appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Data Controller.

The data may also be communicated to Public Bodies, Police Forces or other Public and Private Subjects, but only for the purpose of fulfilling legal obligations, regulations or EU regulations.

Unless otherwise provided through other pages of the site and for which specific information applies, the data collected through the website are processed for the following purposes:

a. to carry out the provision of the services requested by users and the processing of requests for information from users;

b. provide user support;

c. carry out statistical analyses (on an anonymous basis) in order to improve the services offered;

d. for possible registration and management of access to the site;

e. postal dispatch of flyers, brochures, catalogues, invitations or other documentation relating to the services provided and promotional initiatives on products and/or services of Graphistudio, only if expressly requested by the customer/user.

f. comply with the legal obligations consequent to the aforesaid purposes.

g. detection of the index of satisfaction of users (anonymously).

The data may be disclosed, but only in aggregate, anonymous and for statistical purposes.

If the treatment should also involve personal data that fall within the category of “sensitive” data (i.e. data revealing racial and ethnic origin, religious, philosophical or other beliefs, political opinions, membership of parties, trade unions, associations or organizations of a religious, philosophical, political or trade union, as well as personal data disclosing health, life and sexual orientation) or “judicial” (data relating to criminal convictions and crimes) the processing will be carried out within the limits indicated by the General Authorisations of the Guarantor and by subsequent equivalent measures, in the manner provided for by EU Regulation 679/2016 and for the purposes strictly necessary to carry on the relevant activities, the operations relating to the provision of products/services and the fulfilment of contractual and/or legal/regulatory obligations.

Users are invited to avoid the input of unnecessary sensitive and judicial data as this could lead to the destruction of the message.

The processing connected to the web service (“contacts”) of this site takes place at the aforementioned office and are handled only by the owner. The optional, explicit and voluntary sending of electronic mail to the addresses indicated on this site involves the subsequent acquisition of the sender’s address, necessary to respond to requests, and any other personal data included in the message.

Apart from that specified below for navigation data, the user is free to provide personal data included in any information request forms. Failure to provide them may make it impossible to obtain the information requested.

Personal data are processed with automated tools for the time strictly necessary to achieve the purposes for which they were collected. Specific security measures are followed to prevent loss of data, illicit or incorrect use and unauthorized access.

**PERIOD OF RETENTION**

The data are processed and stored for the time required by the purposes for which they were collected. Therefore:

– Personal data (including photographs or videos) collected for purposes related to the execution of a contract between the Owner and the User will be stored until the complete fulfillment of such a contract and also subsequently for legal obligation or to protect or enforce or defend in court a right of the owner.

– When processing is based on the User’s consent, the Data Controller may store personal data for longer until such consent is revoked. In addition, you may be required to retain Personal Information for a longer period of time by law or by order of an authority.

– At the end of the retention period personal data will be deleted. Therefore, at the end of this term, the right of access, cancellation, rectification and the right to portability of data can no longer be exercised.

**RIGHTS OF DATA SUBJECTS**

The subjects to whom the personal data refer have the right at any time to obtain confirmation from the owner of the existence or otherwise of a treatment that concerns them, to request access to personal data, to verify its accuracy or request its rectification, limitation, portability, to oppose the treatment (EU Regulation 679/2016).

Requests should be addressed to the address of the company headquarters, or also by writing to [privacy@graphistudio.com](mailto:privacy@graphistudio.com).

**PLACE OF DATA PROCESSING**

The processing connected to the web services of this site takes place mainly at the headquarters of the owner, as well as in any other place where the parties involved in the processing are located.

**TYPOLOGY OF DATA PROCESSED**  
Information Automatically Collected

The computer systems and software procedures used to operate this website acquire, during their normal operation, some personal data whose transmission is implicit in the communication protocols of the Internet.

This information is not collected to be associated with identified interested parties, but by their very nature could, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to identify the computers used by users who connect to the site, addresses in URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) of requested resources, the time of the request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in reply, the numerical code indicating the status of the response from the server (successful, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the user’s operating system and IT environment.

When you visit the site, the following information is automatically collected:

1\. User’s Hostname. The hostname or Internet Protocol address of the user requesting access to the site.

2\. HTTP header, and the string “user agent” that includes: the type and version of browser used and the operating system with which the browser itself works.

3\. System date. The date and time of your visit.

4\. Complete request. The exact request made by the user.

5\. Content lenght. The size, in bytes, of each document sent to the user.

6\. Method. The request mode used.

7\. Universal Resource Identifier (URI). The location of resources in the server.

8\. The URI Request string, which is everything that is found after the question mark in the URI.

9\. Type of device used to visit the site.

10\. Protocol. The transmission protocol and the version used.

The information automatically collected by Graphistudio through access to the website is used to improve the quality of the service offered to users of the site. This information is collected for the purpose of carrying out statistical surveys (anonymous), to determine which data / content are more or less useful / interesting for users and thus improve the effectiveness of the material available on the site.

Data provided voluntarily by the user

The optional, explicit and voluntary sending of e-mail messages to the addresses indicated on this site involves the subsequent acquisition of the sender’s address, necessary to respond to requests, and any other personal data included in the message.

Apart from what specified for the information collected automatically, the user is free to provide personal data contained in the request forms. Some information is indicated as mandatory, as it is necessary to meet the requests expressed. Failure to provide them may make it impossible to obtain the information requested.

For the direct collection of such data, the visitor will release his or her personal data and consent to the processing of individual services and/or performances requested from Graphistudio, such as: registration on the website or in reserved areas, information requests, course and event subscriptions, newsletters or mailing lists. The consent given may be revoked at any time.

Specific information will be progressively reported or displayed on the pages of the site prepared for particular services on request.

**COOKIES**

**1\. What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small text strings that sites you visit send to your terminal (usually your browser), where they are stored and then retransmitted to the same sites the next time you visit them. While browsing a site, the user can also receive on his terminal cookies that are sent by different websites or web servers (so-called “third parties”), on which may reside some elements (such as, for example, images, maps, sounds, specific links to pages of other domains) on the site that the same person is visiting. Cookies, which are usually present in a very large number of users’ browsers and sometimes have features that allow them to last a long time, are used for different purposes: performing computer authentication, monitoring sessions, storing information on specific configurations regarding users accessing the server, etc..

**2\. Which are the main types of Cookies?**

In this regard, and for the purposes of measure no. 229/2014 of the Privacy Guarantor, two macro-categories have therefore been identified: “technical” cookies and “profiling” cookies.

a. Technical cookies. Technical cookies are those used solely for the purpose of “carrying out the transmission of a communication over an electronic communications network, or to the extent strictly necessary to the provider of an information society service explicitly requested by the subscriber or user to provide that service” (see Article 122, paragraph 1, of the Privacy Code). They are not used for any further purpose and are normally installed directly by the owner or operator of the website. They can be divided into navigation or session cookies, which ensure normal navigation and use of the website (allowing, for example, to make a purchase or authenticate to access restricted areas); analytics cookies, similar to technical cookies when used directly by the site operator to collect information, in aggregate, on the number of users and how they visit the site itself; functionality cookies, which allow the user to navigate according to a series of selected criteria (such as language, products selected for purchase) in order to improve the service provided to the same. The installation of such cookies does not require the prior consent of users.

b. Proliferation cookies. Proliferation cookies are used to create user profiles and to send advertising messages in line with the preferences expressed by the user when browsing the web. Due to the particular intrusiveness that such devices may have within the privacy of users, European and Italian law requires that the user must be adequately informed about the use of the same and thus express their valid consent. Our site does not use specific cookies to profile you.

**Session and Persistent Cookies.**

The Session Cookies, which contain the information that is used in your current browser session. These cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. Nothing is stored on your computer beyond the time you use the site.

Persistent Cookies, which are used to maintain the information that is used in the period between different accesses to the website, or used for technical purposes and to improve navigation on the site. This data allows sites to identify you as a user or visitor already known and adapts accordingly. Persistent” cookies have a longevity that is set by the website and that can vary from a few minutes to several years. Our site does not use this type of cookie. The anti-tracing setting of any browser does not affect the browsing of our site.

**First party and third party cookies.**

It is necessary to take into account the different party that installs the cookies on the user’s terminal, depending on whether it is the same operator of the site that the user is visiting (the so-called “first party”) or a different site that installs cookies through the first (the so-called “third party”). The first part Cookies are created and can be read by the site that created them. Third party cookies, on the other hand, are created and can be read by domains outside the site and the data are stored by the third party. This site uses first-party cookies of a technical nature, so, as mentioned, consent is not required, only this notice is.

For more information about this type of advertising based on clients preferences and resulting from third party cookies, please visit the third party sites below. At [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) and [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) you will also find information on how behavioural advertising works, extensive information on cookies as well as steps required to protect your privacy on the internet.

If you would like to know more about cookies and how to manage them, you can also visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

**Third party cookies**

This Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). For more information you can visit the Google page related to the use of cookies for Analytics (Link).

Google Analytics uses cookies to collect and analyse information about your use of the website (including your IP address) anonymously. The website operator has set up Google Analytics in such a way that your IP address is partially anonymised. This information is transmitted to Google for the purpose of compiling reports on your activity on the website. However, Google does not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google, nor does it attempt to link an IP address with the identity of a computer user. However, Google has developed the browser add-on for deactivating Google Analytics JavaScript ([ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en ](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)) to give website visitors the opportunity to prevent Google Analytics from using their data.

The site allows the use of YouTube, owned by Google Inc., only to allow users of the site to view the content distributed through the YouTube channel of Graphistudio (LINK). More information on how Google uses cookies can be found at [ http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/ ](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/).

The Site also allows you to express your preferences through interaction with other applications (so-called “social”). For example, by clicking on the respective “key” on the pages of the Site, the user can access their Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn, Instagram and Pinterest profiles and express, share or report their preference about the content of the Site. In this case, also in order to understand the use that these applications make of your data, the information prepared by the company owner of said application is valid.

__Facebook__ : [ http://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/ ](http://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [ https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies ](https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies)

__Twitter__ : [ https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en ](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en) – [ https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170519-uso-dei-cookie-e-di-altre-tecnologie-simili-da-parte-di-twitter# ](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170519-uso-dei-cookie-e-di-altre-tecnologie-simili-da-parte-di-twitter%23)

__LinkedIn__ : [ https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy ](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy) – [ https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy ](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

__Instagram__ : [ https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388?helpref=page_content ](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388?helpref=page_content)

__Pinterest__ : [ https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy ](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy)

The owner does not guarantee that the links to the above policies are always active due to updates that do not depend on the owner, so the user is required to browse and verify personally the current text. The owner is not responsible for any malfunction or conditions that do not allow consultation of the policies of these applications.

The longevity of cookies, therefore, ranges from the individual session to two years from visiting the page.

**MANAGEMENT OF COOKIES IN THE CONFIGURATION OF THE MOST WIDELY USED BROWSERS**

The following website is provided again to analyse, in general, and manage your preferences in relation to “online behavioural advertising” [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

Please note that the deactivation or blocking of some cookies may affect the full use of the site or, more generally, its consultation. However, most of the browsers available on the network allow the “anti-tracing” function.
